我是奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years in hell,
我回来只有一个目标
I returned home with only one goal--
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但我之前的方法还不够
But my old approach wasn't enough.
翻译   冰蓝   Michael  迷失星城
我得成为另一个人
I had to become someone else.
我得成为另一个存在
I had to become something else.
翻译    Liv   Silence  小酸奶
我得成为绿箭侠
I had to become the Green Arrow.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously, on "Arrow"...
精校   苹果果    精轴   咖啡Lee
我是不会杀你的
I am not going to kill you,
但是你要相信我  不然我们都会死
but you need to trust me, or we're both dead.
这座城市需要的是
What this city needs is
时间轴风吹来的那片云 校对 Michale 小闪迷路过
一个愿意站出来说话的人
someone willing to stand up in the light of day,
而不是在阴影里游荡的人
not a guy lurking around in the shadows.
特效&后期   咖啡Lee    总监   苹果果
我要竞选市长
I'm going to run for mayor.
真是惊喜啊
What a pleasant surprise.
我想要你救活我妹妹
I want you to bring my sister back to life.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
就算莎拉浸在泉水中  就算那管用
Even if Sara went into the Pit, even if it worked,
从泉水中出来的东西也不再是莎拉
what came out of the Pit would not be Sara.
这方面我们一无所知
We are in uncharted waters here.
我建议你做好最坏的打算
I suggest... you prepare yourself for the worst.
留一些在桌上  朱尼
Leave a couple of those on the table, Junie.
我们不是要送40千克吗
I thought you said we were delivering 40 kilos.
他们会拿到38千克  反正蠢货也不会计算
So they'll get 38. Dumbasses can't count, anyways.
快趴下
Get down, now!
星城警察  趴下
SCPD! On the ground!
安全
Clear!
安全  一切安全
Clear! All clear!
我们可以走了
We're good to go here.
星城警察  举起手来
SCPD, hands in the air!
别紧张  我们搞定了
Relax, we've got this.
你们在这里干什么
What are you guys doing here?
我们没接到紧急救援小组出警的电话
We didn't hear a call from ESU to go out.
你们也不该在这里
You guys aren't supposed to be here, either.
这个嘛
Yeah, well,
一个线人给我们提供了情报
we got a tip from one of our CIs.
王八蛋
Sons of bitches!
我们走
Let's go.
绿 箭
第四季  第四集
真可怕
Well, this is horrible.
哪种秘密巢穴会有窗户啊
What type of secret lair has windows?
奥利弗说他想换一种方式
Well, you know, Oliver said he wanted to do things differently.
我好像看到了一只蟑螂
I think I just saw a cockroach.
关于奥利弗
Listen, about Oliver--
不  没事  他还以为
No, look, it's fine. He still thinks
我们周末去泡温泉了
we spent the weekend at a spa.
我们为什么不能跟他说莎拉的事
But why can't we tell him about Sara?
莎拉需要更多时间
Sara, she needs more time,
我不需要奥利弗评判我
and I don't need Oliver's judgment.
再过几天  她就会跟原来一样了
Just a couple more days, and she'll be back to herself.
我保证
I promise.
我猜他也没告诉你我们来这里干什么啊
Guessing he didn't tell you what we're doing here, either.
没有
No.
他只是在过来的路上一直面带笑容
He just had a perma grin on his face the whole way here.
现在我担心了
Ok, now I'm worried.
他说他要宣布一件大事
He said he had some big announcement to make.
天啊  等等  那在哪儿呢
Oh, my God, wait, where is it?
你怎么没穿戴上
Why aren't you wearing it?
穿戴什么
Wearing what?
你想告诉我们什么
What is that you wanted to tell us?
为什么要在这里宣布
And why are you telling us here?
记得这间办公室吗
Remember this office?
记得  是塞巴斯蒂安·布拉德的竞选办公室
Yes. This was Sebastian Blood's campaign office.
现在是我的了
And now it's mine.
任何够资格的人都害怕竞选
Anyone who's qualified is afraid to run,
是有理由的
for a good reason.
但我可以保护我自己
But I can protect myself.
所以
So...
我要竞选市长
I'm running for mayor.
就没人恭喜我啊
Uh, don't everyone congratulate me at once.
你是认真的啊
Oh, you're serious!
是啊  那周兰斯说这座城市需要
Yes! The other week, Lance was saying that this city needs someone
不是躲在面罩后的人挺身而出  她需要领导
to stand up, who isn't hiding behind a mask. It needs a leader.
但那个人为什么得是你
But why does that person have to be you?
别误会了  我是说你不是政客
I mean, don't get me wrong, but you're not a politician.
也许这是我当选的最好原因
Well, maybe that's the best reason for me to be elected.
你打算怎么找参谋
What are you going to do for a staff,
竞选经理  上哪儿弄钱
or campaign manager--money?
钱的部分搞定了
Money part's taken care of.
帕尔默科技提供了足够的资金给他竞选
Palmer Tech has funded enough to kickstart the campaign.
我的董事会肯定也会对这一决议感到激动
Another decision my board of directors are going to be thrilled with.
你的竞选纲领是什么
What platform are you going to run on?
我会考虑好的
I'll figure it out.
你有什么资格当市长
What qualifies you to be mayor?
我关心这座城市
I care about the city.
但你不能说你要竞选
But you can't say that you're going to run
是因为成为绿箭侠还不够
because being the Green Arrow isn't enough.
我在努力了
I'm working on that.
显然我们要在第一场新闻发布会之前
We are going to brush up on those answers
练习一番这些问题的答案
before the first press conference. Obviously.
我还以为大家会表现得更支持我一点
I kind of thought everyone would be a little bit more supportive.
不是我们不支持  奥利弗  只是
Oh, it's not that we're not supportive, Oliver, it's just that--
我们只是想确保你没有力不从心
We just want to make sure that you're not in over your head.
也许另一个宣布会更好
Maybe the other announcement will go over better.
好吧
Ok...
真的吗
For real?
为什么让费利西蒂买下布拉德的竞选办公室
There's a reason we had Felicity buy Blood's campaign office.
布拉德也需要自己的巢穴
Blood also needed his own lair.
别担心
Don't--don't worry,
我烧了很多香
I--I burned a lot of incense.
奥利弗  你怎么
Oliver, how did you--
你怎么自己做到的
How did you do this all by yourself?
有人帮我
Oh, I had help.
有很多人帮他
He had a lot of help.
西斯科和尖端科研实验室
Cisco and S.T.A.R. Labs.
四套聚碳酸酯装束  根据生物特征进行识别
Four polycarbonate cases, each keyed to your individual biometrics.
天啊  我还以为你不会说"生物特征"呢
Ha! God, I didn't even think you could pronounce "Biometrics."
我有帮忙设计
I had some design input.
奥利弗  这太棒了
Oliver, this is amazing.
我在钢铁厂行动时
Well, when I set up shop in the foundry,
只有我一个人  现在不是这样了
it was just me. That's not the case anymore,
所以我觉得我们需要更大的空间
so I thought we could use a little more space.
那是什么
What was that?
坏了吗
What--did it break?
没有
No.
你没事吧
You ok?
我只是还不习惯这椅子
Yeah, I'm just not used to this chair yet.
通过处理算法  我可以全天接收
I'm feeding police emergency services
警方紧急服务和
and Homeland Security radio transmissions
国安局的无线电广播
through a processing algorithm 24/7.
这样的话  市里一旦发生什么事
This way, if anything happens in the city,
我们马上就会知道
we will--we will know about it.
警告
紧急出警时两名警察被射杀
Two police detectives found shot to death responding to a code three.
没有他们联系调派中心请求支援的记录
Um, there's no record of them calling dispatch for back-up.
也就是说  要么他们的通讯器失效了
Which means either their comms failed
要么他们刚到现场就被埋伏了
or they were ambushed the moment they arrived on the scene.
西娅和我去侦察
Thea and I will do recon,
看看鉴证科在犯罪现场漏了什么
see if there's anything the CSI missed at the crime scene.
好吧  我去找兰斯
All right. I'll talk to Lance.
别提竞选市长的事吧
Maybe skip the part about running for mayor,
我很确定他不会投你一票
because I'm pretty sure you're not going to have his vote.
我要改变他对我的看法
That'll have to change.
没有星城警署的帮助  我无法管理城市
Can't run the city without the help of the SCPD.
好吧
Ok.
西娅觉得你要穿戴什么
What did Thea think that you were wearing?
不知道
No idea.
追查弹道  让鉴证科设法从弹壳上找出指纹
Fast track ballistics and have CSI dust every shell casing for latents.
鉴证科恢复了这张SIM卡的数据
Forensics recovered this SIM card.
可能是其中一个嫌犯的
Probably belongs to one of the doers,
不过他们说至少要两天才能全部查清
but CSU says they need 48 hours to get a full work-up.
什么  死了两个警探的
What? How is evidence in a crime scene
犯罪现场的证据难道还没有最高优先级吗
where two detectives were killed not a top priority?!
人手不够
We don't have the manpower.
你最近来这里的时间
You spend more time here now
比之前因为打伤狗仔队而被拘留的时间还长
than when you were getting collared for hitting paparazzi.
你有空吗
You got a moment for me?
有
Yeah.
你老是来这  难道以后要
So these visits, are they going to be a
每周来一次吗
weekly thing?
我是想要帮忙
Well, I was trying to help with...
那是什么
What's that?
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
市政厅削减了我很大的预算
City Hall has cut my budget so tight,
估计在我八十岁前都拿不到物证报告
I can't get evidence turned around before I'm 80.
我希望我能
I'm hoping that's something
-帮上一些忙  -是吗
- I might be able to help with eventually. - Yeah?
我已经决定要竞选市长了
I've decided to run for mayor.
真的吗
Really?
我知道机会不大
And I know it's a long-shot,
不过如果你能支持我竞选  我会很感激
but it would mean a lot if you would endorse my candidacy.
是是是  当然了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure.
看到了前几任市长的下场
After what happened to the last few mayors,
我希望你能取得大胜利
I'm hoping you win in a landslide.
来自劳雷尔的短信
我需要见你
在那之前  我得赶紧抓到杀警察的人
Till then, I'm trying to catch a cop killer
但我没时间等那人手不足的实验室给我报告了
and I don't have time to wait for my understaffed crime lab.
物证
等天黑了再点火
I want you to wait till nightfall to light a fire.
否则  会引起别人的注意的
Otherwise, you're going to draw attention.
这是干净的水
All right, there's fresh water
从山底的一条小溪接的
coming off a stream at the base of the hill.
往北走十五米就有可以吃的植物了
There's edible plants maybe 50 feet to the north.
不要吃红色的浆果
Hey, do not eat the red berries,
而且也不要让任何人看见你
and do not let anyone see you.
我为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
冒着生命危险救我
Risking your life to save mine?
说来话长
It's complicated.
他们可能认为我死了
They may think I'm dead,
但他们会来找你的
but they're going to come looking for you.
不用他们来找  我会回去的
They're not going to come looking for me. I'm going back to camp.
我观察过他们
I've watched those men.
他们就像亲兄弟一样
They're like brothers to each other.
他们过去有交情  感情很深
They have a history, a bond.
可你不一样
You're not one of them.
所以你要为我做点事
That's why you're going to have to do something for me.
而这事你不会喜欢的
And you're not going to like it.
我想出来了
All right, so I figured it out.
根据数据分析  是尼尔·亚当斯
It's Neal Adams in data processing.
他在夏令营中赢了三次射箭金牌
He won the Archery Medal 3 years running at his summer camp.
他容易发怒
He has a problem with his temper,
而且他喜欢绿色
and he likes the color green.
你觉得尼尔·亚当斯是绿箭侠吗
You think that Neal Adams is the Green Arrow?
他  他身高才1米57
He's--he's 5'2!
是利夫茨吗
Lifts?
我不会告诉你他是谁的
I am not telling you who he is!
对了笨蛋
Oh, and B-T-Dub,
给老板搞恶作剧
next time you want to prank your boss--
会对你的工作很不利  不过无论怎样
worst career move, but whateves--
你最好还是再努力些吧
you might want to try a little harder.
我不明白
And you lost me.
我这周一直收到这东西
I've been receiving these all week.
不是我发的
OK, well, I didn't send this,
相信我  如果我想给你恶作剧的话
and trust me, if I were going to prank you,
我会更有创意的
it would be a lot more creative.
这个代码是2013年的
This code is from 2013.
可是IP地址是帕尔默科技的  从你工作室里的
But the IP address is coming from Palmer Tech, from a terminal here
一台电脑
in your work space.
我觉得我应该说
I believe the term is,
我抓到你现行了
you are so busted.
我没有  也不可能
I'm not busted. I can't be busted.
我没有给你发两年前的代码
I didn't send you two-year-old code.
虽然写得不错
Though it is elegant.
而且很熟悉
And familiar.
我之前在看帕尔默先生的一些原型机
I was going through some of Mr. Palmer's old prototypes,
我发现了这个
and I found this.
那是雷的  我是说帕尔默先生的
That was Ray's. I mean...Mr. Palmer's.
这些代码和你手机上收到的好像是一样的
I mean, this has code that's like identical to what you have on the phone.
可问题是
I mean, the question is,
为什么帕尔默先生的原型机系统给你发短信呢
why is Mr. Palmer's prototype OS sending you texts on your phone?
雷一定是把原型机的电脑
Ray must have connected the prototype's computer
连到了公司的局域网络
to the company's local area network.
没错  它上传了系统崩溃时的日志
It did! It uploaded a crash log.
设备中被设定好了程序
I mean, the equipment's programmed
在发生致命的故障前会记录下用户的语音
to record the user's voice right before a fatal malfunction.
抱歉
Sorry.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
不应该选这个词
Poor choice of words.
关键是  帕尔默先生最后所录的话
The point is, is that Mr. Palmer's last recorded statement
可能能解释他的死因
could shed some light on how he died.
访问拒绝
有密码
Looks like it's password protected.
我已经知道他是怎么死的了
I already know how he died.
我不需要再知道一遍
I don't need to re-live it.
可是
But--
可是  雷和我关系很好
But, Ray and I were close.
我们以前是  朋友
We were friends.
他在半年前去世了
He died 6 months ago.
我真的不想再揭开这个伤口了
I don't really want to open that particular wound.
来自奥利弗的短信
我们查到些东西
又发来了吗
It did it again?
不是
Nope.
另一个难题
Different mystery.
兰斯给了一张从犯罪现场找出的SIM卡
Lance gave us a SIM card recovered from the crime scene.
劳雷尔呢
Where's Laurel?
她说她有点事要处理
She said she had something she needed to deal with.
还好你们最近不缺人手
It's a good thing you guys aren't short handed these days.
这张SIM卡不是手机上的
This SIM card isn't from a cell phone.
好像是某种有GPS的对讲机
Looks like some kind of walkie with GPS.
这么说我们能追踪它了
GPS as in we can track it?
我是说我能查出它都去过什么地方
As in, I can figure out all the places it's been
然后根据这些来确定...
and triangulate from there to determine...
位置
它是从哪来的
where it came from.
穿上装备
Gear up.
五楼安全
Fifth floor is clear.
是的  这地方空无一人
Yeah, this place is completely empty.
我好像有发现  三楼
I think I found something, third floor.
马上过去
Headed your way.
这里所有的门都是开着或者没锁的
Every door here is open or unlocked,
只有这扇不是
except for this one.
安全
Clear.
并不空荡
It's not empty.
M4步枪  防弹衣
M4s, Kevlar,
闪光弹  有些是军用级别的
flash bang grenades. Some of this stuff is military-grade.
难道这是幽灵的武器库吗
Well, do you think we found the Ghost's armory?
不是
No.
星城警署
不是吧
Wait...
星城警署
Star City Police Department.
杀那两个警探的人也是警察
The people who killed those detectives were police officers.
好吧  好吧  我忍不住要问了
All right, all right, I'll bite.
我们来你地下室干什么
What are we doing down in your basement?
还是直接让你看吧
It's better if I just show you.
鉴于去年我们之间发生的事
After what happened between us last year,
我发誓我不会再向你隐瞒什么了
I swore that I would never keep secrets from you again,
尤其是关于我们家人的事
especially when it has to do with our family.
家人
Family?
宝贝
Baby?
这  这怎么可能呢
How is-- how is this even possible?
刺客联盟
The League of Assassins.
他们有种叫复活泉水的东西
They have something called the Lazarus Pit.
可以令人起死回生
It can bring someone back from the dead.
把死人变活吗
Back from what? From the--
她没活  劳蕾尔  你看她
This isn't back, Laurel. Look at her. Look--
你看我的宝贝啊  我不...
look at my baby. I--I don't--
爸爸  她活着
Dad, she's alive.
你女儿活过来了
Your daughter is alive.
这不是我女儿
This isn't my daughter.
爸爸  她是
Daddy, it is.
她只是死去时间有些久
She's just been gone for a really long time.
没关系
It's ok.
她会记起自己是谁的
She'll remember who she is.
我们只需要耐心等待就好
We just have to be patient.
我们会帮她找回自己的  对吗
And we'll help her find her way, right?
你还记得我吗
Do you remember me?
我是劳蕾尔  你姐姐
I'm Laurel, your sister?
看呐
Look.
这是我
There's me,
这是你
and this is you.
看见了吗
Do you see that?
那是谁
And who is that?
是爸爸吗
Is that Daddy?
我们是你的家人
We're your family.
我们爱你
We love you.
我是谁
Who--who am I?
她说话了
She's speaking
因为她开始记起来了
because she's remembering.
劳蕾尔
Laurel!
-你没事吧  -我没事
- You all right? - I'm fine!
她只是...
She just...
她需要更多时间
She needs more time.
我觉得你最好把"给警务人员大换血"
I think you better add "Get an entirely new police force"
加到你的竞选纲领里
to your campaign platform.
并不是整个警局  是的
It's not the entire force, but...
我们不知道谁变质了
we don't know who's compromised.
除了兰斯队长
Except for Captain Lance.
是啊  兰斯队长现在下落不明
Yeah, well, Captain Lance is MIA right now.
我想还是在这个屋子里寻求帮助
I think it's safe to assume that whatever help we're going to get,
会比较可靠
it's right here in this room.
我在努力呢
I'm working on something.
西斯科说我们还应该解决电路问题
Cisco said we were still working out some of the kinks.
在过去两个月里  发生了
In the last two months, there's been a huge spike
帮派偷取其他帮派毒品的大型事件
on gangs stealing drug shipments from other gangs.
但这不是帮派干的  是变质的警察
Yeah, but it's not these gangs, it's these bad cops.
他们偷取其他帮派的毒品
Who steal the drugs to sell them back
然后又卖回给这些帮派
to the gangbangers they stole them from.
既然这些变质的警察想干掉大毒枭
So these corrupt cops are taking down big drug scores.
那我们就送给他们一个
Let's give them one.
怎么做
How?
那要看你跟你以前的毒贩子关系有多好了
That depends on how close you are with your former drug dealer.
选哪一个呢
Depends which one.
我们需要弄些钱
We're going to need some money.
你是说现在的钱还不够吗
Don't you mean more money?
奎尼
Queenie.
好久不见你了
I haven't seen you in forever.
这是你的男朋友吗
This your boyfriend?
是保镖
Bodyguard.
没想到奎恩家的人现在还能请得起保镖啊
Didn't realize the Queens could afford that kind of help these days.
我最近得到了一笔遗产
Well, I recently came into my inheritance
想用这些钱办个派对
and was hoping to throw a party with it.
你能帮我吗
So can you help me out?
要多少...
To the tune of...
80公斤
80 keys?
你知道我的派对是什么样的
You know how I like to party.
我也许能找到中间人
I might have a hook-up.
但他不收信用卡的
But he doesn't take credit cards.
容我打个电话
Let me make a call.
我一直试图联系你
I've been trying to get in touch with you.
是啊  手机关机了
Ah, yeah, phone's been off.
怎么  现在你要告诉你想竞选总统了吗
What, are you going to tell me you're running for president now?
你的警探不是被帮派杀死的
Your detectives aren't dead because of gang violence.
他们是被警察杀的
They were killed by cops.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你给我们的SIM卡  查到了凶手的军械库
The SIM card that you gave us; It led to the killers' armory,
里面所有的装备和武器都是星城警署下发的
and all the equipment, the weapons, it was all SCPD-issued.
他是谁
Who is it?
他可能是警局里的任何人
It could be anyone in the department.
这些人最近一直在搞缉毒行动
These guys have been taking down drug busts.
所以我让西娅弄来了几十公斤可卡因
So I've had Thea procure a couple kilos of cocaine--
你的市长竞选可真是开了个好头
Your mayoral campaign's off to a fantastic start.
我们把毒品放在梅尔德伦的一个仓库里
We're keeping the drugs in a warehouse on Meldrum.
我需要你把这消息放出去
I need you to subtly get the word out.
好
All right.
听我说  等等
Listen, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
他们出现的时候我希望能在场
I want to be there when they show.
我觉得这不是个好主意
I'm not sure that's a good idea.
是  我不知道我是否在乎
Yeah, well, I'm not sure I really give a damn,
但如果我的辖区里出了变质的警察
because if I got bad cops in my precinct,
我要亲自去把他们逮起来
I'm going to be there to bust 'em.
你遇到什么破事了
The hell happened to you?
那个女人想逃跑
The woman tried to escape.
我们追她  但她进了雷区
We chased her, but she went through a minefield.
刚才好像听见了爆炸声
Thought I heard an explosion earlier.
那个炸死了理查德
That one got Richards.
混账
Son of a bitch.
不过我还是抓住她了
I caught her... eventually.
让她长记性了
Made it memorable.
怎么  我该杀了她  不是吗
What, I'm supposed to kill her, right?
她该死  而不是理查德
Her, yeah. Richards, not so much.
我没杀了理查德  我告诉你了
I didn't kill Richards. I told you--
是地雷  我知道了
A landmine. I know.
你知道有意思的是什么吗
You know what's funny?
我们在这里待了几个月都相安无事
We've been here months without a problem,
而你一来就有两个人被地雷炸死了
and here you come and two guys get wasted by landmines.
你这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
意思是我想见她
It means I want to see her.
那个女人
The woman.
我要看到尸体
I want to see the body.
好
Ok.
我知道这是个陷阱
I know this is a trap and all,
但涉及到毒品
but something about the drugs,
俱乐部...
the club...
让我觉得好像又回到了高中
Makes me feel like I'm back in high school again.
怎么了
What?
只是在想
Just thinking about
我真是不愿意让女儿在这里长大
how much I hate raising a daughter in this city.
注意
Heads up!
有辆卡车正在向你们接近
I'm reading a truck closing in on your position.
车型符合紧急救援小组的警车
The make matches a profile for an ESU strike vehicle.
收到  准备好了
Copy, we're ready.
-还有两分钟  -兰斯队长
- Two minutes out. - Captain Lance.
怎么  就我一个人没有暗号吗
What, I don't get a code name like the rest of you?
警探...准备
Detective... Get ready.
目标出现  行动
Target's on site. Let's go.
敌人火力强大  行动
We've got multiple Tangos, move!
反恐特警
撤退
Move out!
你还好吗
You ok?
经过训练  还有这些装备
The training, the equipment,
他们都是警察
those were cops.
不  我不好
And no, I'm not ok.
你一定是在耍我
You have got to be kidding me.
不  不是跟你抱怨
Oh, no, um, not to complain,
但你知道你把一个警察队长
but you do know that you just brought a police captain
带进我们的秘密藏身处
into our secret lair?
别担心  我手上的证据已经足够关你25年
Don't worry; I got enough to put you away for 25 years.
说笑的
Kidding.
我们要担心的警察不是兰斯队长
Captain Lance isn't the police we should be worried about.
难怪警队里有腐败现象
Wow. No wonder there's corruption on the force.
其他人都有更好的资源
Everyone else has got better resources.
真想不到
I don't know.
今天紧急救援小组手上的武器真是大开眼界
Those ESU had some pretty fancy toys tonight.
这绝对不是标准的警察装备
That definitely weren't standard police issue.
是警察的装备
Well, they were police issue, all right,
只不过不是标准的
but just not standard.
那些都是专业抓捕治安维护者特别小组的装置
Those were specialized Anti-Vigilante Task Force gear.
特别小组不是解散了吗
I thought the Task Force was disbanded.
是  我又恢复了小组
Yeah, I might have reinstated that,
去年的事吧
last year.
有几名警官参与
How many officers are there?
四十人左右
40 or so.
这范围绝对缩小了一点
Well, that definitely narrows things down a bit.
我们应该检查他们的安排记录
We should check their conduct records.
也许可以把范围再缩小一点
Maybe that'll narrow it down a little bit more.
这次要比平时花费的时间久
Yeah, that's going to take a little bit longer than usual.
我可以给你无限制的权限
Well, I can give you unrestricted access
让你访问警局的计算机网络
to the department's computer network.
也许会让你查得快一点
Might speed things up a little.
我去看看在分局里能有什么发现
I'll see what I can dig up at the precinct.
好像是八十个钥匙
Looks like 80 keys here.
那些白痴在捕鼠器上放真芝士做诱饵
Idiots baited the mouse trap with real cheese.
因为他们知道我们会发现他们的
Because they knew we'd sniff them out otherwise.
还好我们决定挑选特别装备
Well, it's a good thing we decided to pack the special gear.
今晚来这突袭的不止我们
We weren't the only ones showing up with a little surprise tonight.
兰斯队长
Captain Lance?
他不可能把我们当作警察
There's no way he didn't peg us as cops.
我们要干掉他
We got to take him out.
我们不杀警察
We don't kill cops.
去跟我们昨天干掉的那两个警察说这话吧
Tell that to the two gold shields we wasted last night.
他们是错误的时间出现在错误的地方
They were in the wrong place at the wrong time.
我是不会冷血无情地杀害警察同僚
I'm not killing fellow officers in cold blood.
我们的优势是警方认为我们是犯罪团伙
Our advantage was the force thought we were gangbangers.
这件事我们应该投票
We should put this to a vote.
要我投票  枪在谁手里
My vote? Nine millimeters,
谁就说了算
and the only one that counts.
我们不是罪犯  大家都记住这点
We are not criminals. Let's all just try to remember that.
我们之所以这么做  是因为这座城市濒临死亡
We went this route because the city is dying,
我们要有能力保护我们的家人
and we need to be able to provide for our families.
仍然无法改变兰斯是个麻烦的事实
Still doesn't change the fact that Lance is a problem.
他不是
No, he's not.
他是解决办法
He's a solution.
柯蒂斯
Curtis?
你来了
There you are!
为什么你一直没回我的短信
Why haven't you been answering my texts?
你的短信写着紧"急情况"  "天呐"
Your texts were "911," "OMG,"
"尽快"  还有五个感叹号
"ASAP," and five exclamation points.
我没时间回复这种
I do not have time to respond to something
连实际文字都没有的短信
that doesn't contain at least one actual word.
我要你帮我弄弄帕尔默先生的系统崩溃日志
I need your help with Mr. Palmer's crash log.
不是告诉过你别管了吗
I thought I told you to let that go.
我试过强行破译密码  但是没用
Look, I've tried brute forcing a password, but nothing works.
但是有一个包含了程序员记录的代码
But there is a subkernel that contains a programmer note.
天呐  这肯定就是一直在说的东西
Oh, my God, this must be what talking to me is like.
程序员记录显示你知道密码
And that programming note suggests that you know the password.
这倒是合乎情理  你和帕尔默先生曾经是朋友
I mean, which makes sense, right? You and Mr. Palmer were friends.
没错  我知道密码
Yeah, I know the password.
你知道  就是说我们能
You do? So tell it to me so we can--
不  我
No! I...
我不想听我前男友的
I do not want to listen to a recording
临终遗言录音
of my ex-boyfriend's final moment before he died.
你曾经和帕尔默先生在一起
You and Mr. Palmer were together?
现在你明白我为什么不愿听到他的声音了吧
Now do you understand why I don't want to hear his voice?
不
No.
我弟弟六年前去世
My brother died six years ago.
因为胰脏癌
Pancreatic cancer.
能够听到
To be able to hear
他以前从未说过的话
something from him I've never heard before...
天呐  我愿用一切交换
God, I'd-- I'd give anything.
兰斯队长
Captain Lance.
很高兴收到你的短信
What a pleasure it was to receive your message.
你开始联系我
And for you to initiate contact, well,
让我觉得我们的关系迈出了重要一步
made me feel like our relationship took an important step forward.
我需要你的帮忙
I need your help.
对不起  再说一次
I'm sorry, say that again.
是为了你的女儿
It's for my daughter.
不是你用来要挟我的那个
Not the one that you're holding over me as leverage.
莎拉  你去年失去的那个
Sara, the one you lost last year.
她复活了
Yeah, she's back.
是因为那个叫复活泉水的东西
This thing called the Lazarus Pit.
我想你一定听说过
I'm sure you've heard of it.
怎么  你调查过我
What, you did your homework on me;
难道你以为我就不会查查你吗
you don't think I did a little digging around on you?
你以前是刺客联盟的成员
You used to be a member of the League of Assassins.
你想怎样  兰斯先生
What is it you want, Mr. Lance?
我的女儿
It's my daughter.
她不对劲
She's not right.
虽然她复活了  但是变得不一样  她疯了
She's-- she's come back and she's different. She's crazy!
她能复活就已经是个奇迹了
It's a miracle she came back at all.
但是感觉不像是奇迹
It doesn't feel like a miracle. All right?
现在你清楚这件事了  我能做些什么
Now you know about this stuff. Is there anything I can do?
你能做些什么
Is there anything that you can do?
我可以给你点建议  以同为父亲的身份
I can give advice, father to father.
我可以告诉你  如果那是我的女儿
I can tell you that if it were my daughter,
我会杀死她
I'd put her down.
她是我的宝贝女儿
She's my baby girl.
她不是  也许她和你女儿长得很像
No, she isn't. She may look like your daughter,
但是她已经无法控制自己的灵魂
but she doesn't possess her soul.
最能表现你爱她的事
The most loving act you can commit
就是让莎拉得到安息
is to return Sara to her final rest.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的很高兴我们回来
Oh, I am so glad we came back.
你没事吧
You all right?
你又这样
You're doing that,
又皱眉了
crinkly thing with your eyebrows.
只是工作上的事  没什么大不了的
Oh, just, no, just something at work. It's no big deal.
这个很重要
this work. Big deal.
丽莎·沃纳
Liza Warner.
我们的电脑坏了  所以我用
I pulled her SCPD personnel file
我在帕尔默科技的电脑调出她星城警方的个人资料
using my computer at Palmer Tech since ours is fritzing.
她是三年前抓捕治安维护者的
One of the original recruits
特别小组里第一批招募的成员之一
to the Anti-Vigilante Task Force over 3 years ago.
由兰斯队长亲自挑选
Hand-picked by then Detective Lance.
她是嫌疑犯吗
Do we think she's a suspect?
我认为沃纳警官
I think that Sergeant Warner
最近三个月在海外银行账户
has deposited over a quarter of a million dollars
存入了超过25万美元
into offshore bank accounts in the last three months.
我们怎样才能找到她
Where can we find her?
我正在着手
I am working on that.
我利用兰斯队长给我们网络权限
I used the network access that Captain Lance gave us
而且警局里每一辆警车的摄像头
and I turned on every uniform and squad car camera
我已经打开了十二小时
on the force in the last 12 hours.
我正在用面部识别软件搜索沃纳
I'm running facial recognition looking for Warner.
你看到什么吗
Do you see something?
不  看到一个人
No, someone.
暂停
Pause.
放大
Zoom in.
和兰斯在说话的这个人
The man that Lance is talking to...
是达米恩·达克
That's Damian Darhk.
你知道我有心脏病吧
You know I got a heart condition, right?
这几年来  你非常蔑视我
For years, you've looked at me with such contempt.
无比轻蔑
Utter disdain.
所以我想...
So I'm wondering...
现在我的脸上是不是也有同样的神情
do I have that same look on my face now?
你在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
我在说你
I'm talking about you...
和达米恩·达克
and Damian Darhk.
这  这...
OK, it's, it's--
我不知道你到底知不知道他是谁
I didn't know if you knew who he was,
或者他对这个城市做了些什么
or what he's been doing to this city.
现在我看到你脸上的表情
And now I see this look on your face.
你懂的
You know.
这很复杂
It's complicated.
不  不复杂
No, it's not.
你知道他杀了多少人吗
Do you have any idea how many people he's killed?
我比你清楚多了
Yeah, I got more of an idea than you.
听着  你们所有人
And listen, you, you of all people,
你们不能就这么来到我家
you don't get to come in to my house
对我妄加评论  懂吗
and pass judgment on me, all right?!
不  你一直觉得自己高我一等
No, you always held yourself out as better than me.
更正义
More righteous.
以前的确是这样
And you were.
直到今晚
Until tonight.
其实我跟达克已经合作了
Actually, it's been a little more than two months now,
两个多月
me working with Darhk.
出发点是好的
It started out benign.
他说他有资源
He said he had resources;
他有人脉  钱财
he had people, money.
他把自己包装成了一个
He held himself out as just another guy
想帮助这座城市的人
who wanted to help this city.
而我们需要帮助
And we needed the help.
你当时并不在
You weren't here.
等我弄清楚他到底是什么货色是...
By the time I figured out who he was, what he was...
那时他威胁了劳蕾尔
that's when he threatened Laurel.
劳蕾尔能照顾好自己  你见识过她的本事
Laurel can take care of herself. You see what she does out there.
当初对于莎拉我也是这么认为的...
That's what I thought about Sara, too--
住嘴  住嘴
Stop, stop it!
不要再躲在你女儿们的身后了
Stop hiding behind your daughters!
她们会为你现在的所作所为不齿
They would be ashamed of what you're doing right now.
你不知道我经历了什么
You don't know what I'm going through.
我竞选市长的一大理由就是因为你
You were the main reason behind me running for mayor!
我内心中
A part of me
有一部分一直想让你看看真正的我
has always wanted you to see what kind of man I really am.
我没想到
I didn't expect
最后反而看清了真正的你
to wind up finding out what kind of man you really are.
你准备怎么办
What are you going to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
你怎么下手的
How'd you do it?
你怎么杀那个女人的
Kill the woman. How'd you do it?
掐死了
Strangled her.
你不是说你做得
I thought you said you made it--
怎么说的来着  很有纪念意义
what was that word-- memorable.
她绝对不会忘掉
She won't forget it.
怎么了
What?
你要跟我求婚吗
You going to propose?
你看上去不像第一次杀人的样子
You don't sound like a guy who just committed his first murder,
我猜你在那个贵族寄宿学校
and I'm guessing you didn't have too many opportunities
不会有太多这种机会吧
in that posh boarding school you grew up in.
你觉得我是在撒谎吗
You think I'm lying?
我觉得如果你没撒谎  那你就是一名冷血杀手
I think if you're not, then you're a stone cold killer.
即使你没有了结她  即使你在糊弄我...
Even if you didn't off her, even if you're messing with me--
当然我不建议你这么做
which I do not recommend...
但我可以在你眼中看到
I see it in your eyes.
瑞特也看到了
Reiter saw it, too.
也许他正是因此才招了你
It's probably why he recruited you.
看到了什么
Saw what?
你是一名阴暗的混蛋
You are one dark bastard.
你内心中有非常冷酷的东西
Something very cold inside of you.
你很害怕
You're terrified of it.
康克林  告诉我
OK, Conklin, tell me something.
如果我是这么阴暗的人...
If I'm this dark person...
你不是应该怕我吗
shouldn't you be afraid of me?
不
Nah.
我跟你一模一样
I'm the exact same way.
如果你敢对我撒谎  你就知道我是什么人了
If you're lying to me, you're going to find that out.
签得不错
Nice sign.
今天早上送来的
Arrived this morning.
你没事吧
You all right?
在想事情
Just thinking.
想什么
About?
像孩子一样去玩哨兵游戏
Going to Sentinel Games as kids.
你还记得派普体育场吗
Do you remember Papp Stadium?
当然了
Oh, yeah.
我超喜欢那个爆米花
I loved the popcorn.
一个哨兵玩家击中守卫时
Every time a Sentinels player hit a homer,
体育场中每个人都会站起来欢呼
every single person in that stadium stood and cheered.
每一个人
Every single one.
团结一心
United.
我想竞选市长
And I wanted to run for mayor
是因为我想领导这座城市
because I wanted to be the leader of that city.
想吗
Wanted?
西娅  我不知道当初那座城市的影子还在不在
Thea, I don't know if that city exists anymore.
我觉得也许已经无法挽回了
I think that it might be beyond saving.
你想说什么
So what are you saying?
我不需要竞选市长
That I don't have to run for mayor.
对不起  宝贝  但是你不是她
I'm sorry, baby, but you're not her.
你不是她
You're not her.
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  你在干什么
Dad, what the hell are you doing?
我在做我该做的事
I'm doing what I got to do.
你根本不知道我能为你们俩做出多么可怕的事
You got not idea what terrible things I would do for both of you.
不  不  你不能杀你自己的女儿
No, no, you are not going to kill your own daughter.
她不是我的女儿
She's not my daughter!
爸爸  她是莎拉
Dad, it's Sara.
没事的
It's OK.
天啊
Oh, God.
爸爸
Dad.
我在干什么  我在干什么
What am I doing? What am I doing?
没事的
It's OK!
我在干什么
What am I doing?!
看着我  没事的  没事的
Look at me, it's OK. It's OK.
我在干什么
What am I doing?
对不起  宝贝  对不起
I'm sorry, baby. I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
兰斯队长
Captain Lance.
丽莎  你在这干什么
Liza. What-- what are you doing here?
我听说你在找我
I heard you were looking for me.
所以想帮你省点力气
Thought I'd make it easier for you.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
爸爸
Dad!
不得入内
私人领地
你来过这里吗
Ever been here before?
这是星城警局处理违禁品的地方
It's the SCPD's contraband disposal facility.
几千斤大满贯  迷魂药  海洛因  全在这里处理
Thousands of pounds of Slam, Vertigo, heroin, all incinerated.
简直就是烧钱
That's just literally burning money.
这地方只有分局局长才能授权进来
Yeah, and the site requires the precinct captain to gain access,
那是不可能的
and that's not happening.
你想干什么  昆汀
What was your plan, Quentin?
你要知道  这个城市已经摇摇欲坠
You have to know the city's dying.
你就准备坐在
Were you just going to stay
你的办公桌前放任一切消失吗
at your desk until there was no city left.
告诉你我不会做什么
I'll tell you what I wasn't going to do--
我不会像你这样玷污这个警徽
I wasn't going to dishonor the badge like you have.
我不是圣人  但我至少不是罪犯
I'm no Saint, but at least I'm not a criminal.
我也不是  我只是一个
Neither am I. I'm just a desperate cop
被逼到角落的绝望的警察
that got backed into too tight a corner.
已识别出
我们知道些什么
What do we know?
丽莎·沃纳和她的手下
Liza Warner and her posse
在劳蕾尔的公寓把兰斯带走
took Lance outside of Laurel's apartment.
我们一定要找到我父亲
We need to find my father.
我还在努力  只是有点阻碍
I'm working on it. Just a little hampered.
系统失灵前  我查到了线索
I think I got something before the latest glitch.
兰斯队长的卡刚在三分钟前刷入星城警署的
Captain Lance's ID was just to access the SCPD contraband
禁运品处置设施
disposal facility 3 minutes ago.
谢谢你  昆汀
Thank you, Quentin.
很抱歉  等到他们找到你时
Sorry about all the paperwork you'll have to fill out
你又要写很多报告了
when they find you.
温馨提醒  现在就打爆我脑袋吧
Word of advice-- put a bullet in my head now
否则我不会放过你
'cause I am coming after you with everything.
他们找到你时  我们早就离开了
By the time they find you, we'll be long gone.
我们要跟其他人一样离开这座城市了
We're leaving this city like everybody else.
新的频率  同样的喊声
New frequency, same cry.
赶紧离开这里
Let's get out of here!
沃纳警官
Sergeant Warner,
你辜负了这座城市
you have failed this city.
你只有这点能耐吗
Is that all you got?
不
Nope.
赶紧离开
Get out of here.
我只要用力  你的脊髓就会断裂
All I got to do is push and I'll sever your spinal cord.
你不会那么做的  丽莎
But you're not going to do it, Liza.
你说过你不是罪犯
You said you're not a criminal.
你杀了他  你就成了罪犯
You kill that man, you are.
我告诉过你我不是罪犯
I told you I wasn't a criminal.
但我也告诉过你我很绝望
But I also told you I was desperate.
谁何尝不是
We all are.
居住在这座城市
Living in this city,
面对现在这一切
dealing with what we're dealing with right now?
大家都会绝望
We're all desperate.
都会被迫走上绝路
We've all been made to do desperate things.
做出可怕的事
Terrible things.
但我必须相信
But I got to believe
我们不会越过底限
that we are not beyond redemption.
我必须相信这座城市还有救
And I got to believe that this city can still be saved.
因为如果我们不再相信
'Cause once we stop believing,
这座城市就真的完蛋了
that's when this city really dies.
而我们也会一起陪葬
And us, us, right along with it.
也许我们仅仅能做的是
Maybe, just maybe,
先拯救自己
we start saving our home
再拯救家园
by saving ourselves first.
所以我们必须面对自己的错误
And that means facing up to our mistakes.
面对司法公正
That means facing justice.
你穿上那套制服
You put on that uniform
是因为你相信司法公正
'cause you believe in justice.
扪心自问  沃纳...
Ask yourself, Warner...
你是否还相信着呢
is that still the case?
执法吧
Do what you got to do.
你知道你的米兰达权利吧
I guess you know your Miranda rights.
「即:你有权保持缄默
但你所说的每一句话
都将作为呈堂证供」
你现在可以进出自如了吗
You got your own key or something?
你对沃纳所说的话救了我一命
What you said to Warner saved my life.
我不知道你如此能言善道
I... I didn't know you had such a way with words.
仅此一次
Well, I don't do encores.
你相信你所说的话吗
You believe what you said?
没错  由头至尾
Yeah. Every word.
尤其是面对司法公正那部分
Especially the part about facing justice.
纽约警局总部今早开门时
When One Police Plaza opens this morning,
我就会去自首
I will be there turning myself in.
我不能让你那么做
I can't have you do that.
我们都无法接近达克
We haven't been able to get close to Darhk.
只有你能
You have.
我希望你维持现状
I'd like you to stick around.
做我们的内应
Stay on the inside.
只有你相信我  这才是个巧妙的计划
Well, that's only a smart plan if you can trust me.
我相信那个说我们必须相信
I trust the man who said we can't stop believing
我们可以拯救这座城市的人
we can save this city.
我没说错...
Like I said--
冷血杀手
stone cold killer.
你满意了吗
You satisfied?
把尸体处理掉
Get rid of the body.
这个洞穴也许还有用处
This cave might be useful for something.
没事了
It's OK.
你没事了
You're ok.
你从哪学会这些的
How did you-- where did you learn to do that?
我在这里学的
I learned it here.
我并不是一直一个人待在这座岛上
I haven't always been alone on this island.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
天呐  他来了
Oh, my God, he's here.
你好吗  我是奥利弗·奎恩
How you doing, man? Oliver Queen.
你好
Hi there.
有你们在这里
It's absolutely wonderful
真的很美妙
that-- that all of you are-- are here.
美妙的事
Just-- just wonderful.
而且很意外
And surprising.
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
是你...  请他们来的吗
Did you... did you hire all of these people?
不  他们只是来实习的  奥利
No, that's what makes them interns, Ollie.
你从哪找来这么多实习生
Where did we get all of these interns?
想在社交媒体上面拥有很多追随者
Easiest way to get a lot of followers on social media
就必须有个非常成功的俱乐部
is to own a very successful club.
我只要告诉他们我三年前就知道的事
All I had to do was tell them what I've already known for 3 years.
奥利弗·奎恩要拯救这座城市
Oliver Queen is going to save this city.
这是什么
What's this?
这是你的演讲稿
This your speech.
今天下午你要宣布你参选
You're announcing your candidacy this afternoon,
你很久没穿西装了  赶紧去翻出来吧
so you better get your suit out of moth balls.
这是你写的吗
Did you write this?
我只是记录下来
I wrote it down.
你告诉过我
Just with what you told me,
要团结这座城市
about this city being united.
团结
United.
这座城市以前就是那样
That's what this city used to be.
所以她可以变回那样
It's what it can be.
所以她必须变回那样
It's what it must be again.
我知道我不是当市长的理想人选
Now, I know that I'm not the obvious choice for mayor.
我不是政治家
I'm-- I'm not a politician.
我把家族企业转让给别人了
I signed away my family's company.
我大学也没毕业
I didn't even graduate from college,
不过我得辩解一下
although, in my defense,
我上了四间大学
I did go to four of them.
我没有领袖的背景
I certainly don't have a traditional background for leadership,
但我要告诉你们
but I can tell you this--
在地狱待了五年
after five years in hell,
我回到家园只有一个目的
I returned home with only one goal.
我要拯救整座城市
I wanted to save my city.
在大家的帮助下
And with your help,
我才能实现
I can.
在你们的帮助下  我们重建家园
With your help, we will restore our home
我们知道她可以成为炫耀夺目的城市
to the shining beacon we know it can be.
我们知道我们怎么能实现这个目标
But how we're going to get there isn't a mystery.
我们会在朋友  家人和爱人的
We will overcome our challenges with help from our friends,
帮助下
our family,
克服这些困难
our loved ones.
密码
允许访问
对不起  费利西蒂  这是我的错
I'm sorry, Felicity, this is my fault.
我们相信的人
Those we trust,
为了取得胜利我们需要再次相信的人
and those we will need to trust again in order to prevail.
因为要恢复
Because the only way
我们家园过去的风光
that we are going to return our home to greatness
我们必须齐心协力
is to do so together.
团结
United.